Hello everyone, welcome back to another great lesson here at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
Hello everyone.
大家好。
And today we've got a great lesson for you at the upper intermediate level.
今天我们为大家准备了一堂中高级水平的精彩课程。
We're going to be talking about an interesting topic which is gambling.
我们将讨论一个有趣的话题——赌博。
Yeah, I don't know if you like to do this, Marco.
是啊，我不知道你是否喜欢这个，Marco。
Go, you know, play some cards, play some poker, blackjack, throw the dice.
比如，打打牌、玩扑克、二十一点、掷骰子。
I'm actually a bit of a fan of the roulette.
我其实有点喜欢轮盘赌。
You have to throw the ball onto the wheel that's spinning and it lands into like a
你得把球扔到旋转的轮盘上，然后它落进一个
little compartment in a number.
带数字的小格子里。
Right.
没错。
So you can win like based on the number and the color.
所以你可以根据数字和颜色赢钱。
But it's interesting because if you get the number right, it pays you 35 times your bet.
但有趣的是，如果你猜对了数字，它会赔给你赌注的35倍。
Wow, that's a lot of money to win.
哇，那能赢好多钱啊。
A lot of potential there, but there's a lot of numbers on that wheel.
潜力很大，但轮盘上的数字也很多。
But that's the thing.
但问题就在这儿。
Some people like gambling, some people don't like it.
有些人喜欢赌博，有些人不喜欢。
And in some countries, in some states, it's illegal, right?
而且在一些国家、一些州，赌博是非法的，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So today we're talking about a city that's looking to legalize this sport.
所以今天我们讨论的是一个正在考虑将这项活动合法化的城市。
So we're going to take a listen.
那我们就来听听看。
Here at One Time, when we come back, we're talking all about what's going on in today's
在One Time这里，我们回来后会讨论今天课程中
lesson.
的所有内容。
Did you hear?
你听说了吗？
The state is thinking of legalizing gambling in our city.
州里正在考虑在我们城市将赌博合法化。
Soon we're going to have amazing hotels and casinos here, which will be good for business.
很快我们就会有豪华酒店和赌场，这对生意有好处。
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗？
Gambling is a vice industry built on deception and fed by the intentional exploitation of
赌博是一种建立在欺骗之上的邪恶行业，靠故意利用
human weakness for the sole purpose of monetary gain.
人性的弱点来牟利。
It disgusts me.
这让我感到恶心。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么呢？
How does it exploit people?
它怎么剥削人了？
Well, to begin with, gambling is addictive.
嗯，首先，赌博会让人上瘾。
It ruins marriages, destroys families and bankrupts communities.
它破坏婚姻、摧毁家庭、让社区破产。
Once you're addicted, it's very difficult to stop.
一旦上瘾，就很难戒掉。
People have lost their houses, cars and have been left out on the street after becoming
人们失去房子、车子，上瘾后
addicted.
流落街头。
Secondly, it exploits because men become addicted to gambling most often because of the action
其次，它剥削人，因为男人上瘾通常是因为
and risk.
刺激和冒险。
Women gamble to escape and senior citizens will start gambling for social interaction.
女人赌博是为了逃避，老年人赌博是为了社交。
Underage gamblers often start gambling on sports with friends and then illegal bookies.
未成年赌徒通常从和朋友赌体育开始，然后找非法庄家。
Geez, now that I think about it, maybe legalizing gambling isn't such a good idea.
天哪，现在想想，也许把赌博合法化不是个好主意。
Although I have been to Las Vegas and I didn't become addicted or anything like that.
虽然我去过拉斯维加斯，也没上瘾什么的。
You cannot predict who will become addicted to gambling.
你无法预测谁会染上赌瘾。
Now excuse me, I have a protest rally to organize.
现在请原谅，我得去组织抗议集会了。
All right, so a very strong opinions against gambling, right?
好吧，所以对赌博有非常强烈的反对意见，对吧？
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
So we've got someone who hasn't really thought it through and another person who has thought
所以我们有一个人没怎么深思熟虑，另一个人却想得
way too much about what's going on.
太多了。
Right.
没错。
And well, he did point out some very interesting arguments against gambling.
而且，他确实提出了一些反对赌博的很有意思的论点。
And so we're going to take a look at some of the language that person used today in
所以我们来看看那个人今天在“语言要点”环节中使用的
Language Takeaway.
一些语言。
语言要点。
Well, this first one we've got here is a word that has to do with the topic of today's lesson.
嗯，我们这里的第一个词与今天课程的主题有关。
So legalizing gambling.
也就是将赌博合法化。
What does it mean to legalize?
合法化是什么意思？
Right.
没错。
So to legalize, to make it legal.
所以合法化，就是让它变得合法。
So legal is the word that refers to law.
所以legal这个词指的是法律。
And so that means to make something okay.
这意味着让某事变得可以接受。
It means to allow something in a state or country.
意味着在一个州或国家允许某事。
Exactly.
没错。
In many countries, it's illegal to gamble.
在许多国家，赌博是非法的。
So in this case, the city is looking to legalize it to make it legal.
所以在这个案例中，这个城市正在考虑将其合法化，让它变得合法。
All right.
好吧。
So many young people in America would like to see this law changed.
所以美国很多年轻人希望看到这项法律改变。
You're not allowed to drink until you're 21 years old, drink alcohol that is.
你21岁之前不能喝酒，我是说酒精饮料。
So they would like to see the legalization of underage drinking.
所以他们希望看到未成年人饮酒合法化。
Now is it 21 in all states or in the majority?
现在是所有州都21岁，还是大多数州？
Yes, all states.
是的，所有州。
Really?
真的吗？
I thought it was only in some of them.
我以为只有一些州是这样。
No, it changed in the late 70s, I think.
不，我想是在70年代末改变的。
But you absolutely cannot drink until you're 21.
但你绝对要到21岁才能喝酒。
Wow.
哇。
What do you think?
你怎么看？
Is that okay or is that?
这样好吗，还是说……
I think that it encourages young people to drink irresponsibly.
我认为这鼓励年轻人不负责任地喝酒。
And so I believe we should legalize drinking at the age of 18 because it would make people
所以我相信我们应该把饮酒年龄合法化到18岁，因为这样会让人们
learn how to be more responsible.
学会更负责任。
Right.
没错。
Interesting.
有意思。
All right.
好吧。
So we want to legalize underage drinking.
所以我们想将未成年人饮酒合法化。
English fun.
英语真有趣。
All right.
好吧。
No, let's not manipulate my words.
不，别曲解我的话。
This next word is very, very important.
下一个词非常重要。
He's saying that gambling or the gambling industry exploits people.
他说赌博或赌博行业剥削人。
Okay, exploit.
好的，剥削。
You might have heard this in the news before.
你可能以前在新闻里听过这个词。
We talk about often in the news, the exploitation of people.
我们经常在新闻里谈到剥削人。
But in this case, we're talking about exploiting people through money and gambling.
但在这个案例中，我们讨论的是通过金钱和赌博剥削人。
Right.
没错。
So to exploit basically is to take advantage of them.
所以剥削基本上就是利用他们。
To use them for something.
利用他们来获取某种东西。
Not to treat them as people, but to use them as a way to get something.
不把他们当人看，而是把他们当作获取利益的手段。
All right.
好吧。
And we often hear about it, as you say, in news about, you know, factories or companies
而且我们经常听到，就像你说的，在新闻里关于工厂或公司
exploiting their employees or something of the sort.
剥削员工之类的报道。
We can also exploit the earth for its resources by taking oil and taking diamonds and taking
我们也可以剥削地球的资源，比如开采石油、钻石和
gold.
黄金。
Okay.
好的。
So to take advantage of.
所以就是利用。
Interesting.
有意思。
So to exploit is the verb, but exploitation is the noun.
所以exploit是动词，exploitation是名词。
All right.
好吧。
That's the thing.
问题就在这儿。
So we talk about the exploitation of people in this country or the exploitation of the
所以我们谈论这个国家剥削人，或者
earth.
剥削地球。
And they're talking about how gambling exploits people and how it's a vice.
他们讨论赌博如何剥削人，以及它如何是一种恶习。
Ooh, vices.
哦，恶习。
So for those of you Christians out there, you might be very familiar with the sins,
所以对于基督徒来说，你们可能很熟悉罪孽，
right?
对吧？
The seven deadly sins.
七宗罪。
Well, these are all vices, things that you do that are bad.
嗯，这些都是恶习，你做的不好的事情。
So drinking too much is a vice.
所以喝太多酒是一种恶习。
Right.
没错。
Or eating too much, right?
或者吃太多，对吧？
Right.
对。
Or spending money without having money may be a vice for you.
或者没钱还花钱，对你来说可能是个恶习。
So addictions are also a type of vice, right?
所以成瘾也是一种恶习，对吧？
Like drinking, smoking, or drug abuse.
比如喝酒、抽烟或吸毒。
Exactly.
没错。
These are all vices.
这些都是恶习。
So vice is a bad thing.
所以恶习是坏事。
Now, we may remember this show, popular American show called Miami Vice.
现在，我们可能记得一部剧，一部很受欢迎的美剧叫《迈阿密风云》。
So what is that?
那是什么？
Ooh, well, Miami Vice, it's in the city of Miami and it's about police officers.
哦，嗯，《迈阿密风云》，故事发生在迈阿密市，讲的是警察。
So in the police, there's sometimes a group called the vice squad.
所以在警察部门里，有时会有一个叫风化组的团队。
These are people who go out and try and stop people who are doing things that are vices.
这些人出去试图阻止那些做恶习之事的人。
Like drugs and gambling and stuff like that.
比如毒品、赌博之类的东西。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
Vice squad.
风化组。
Interesting.
有意思。
All right.
好的。
So in the language takeover, we have this interesting word, a bookie.
所以在“语言小课堂”里，我们有一个有趣的词，bookie（赌注经纪人）。
All right.
好的。
So if any of you like to go to the horse races, you might be familiar with this one.
所以如果你们中有人喜欢去赛马场，可能对这个词很熟悉。
A bookie is someone who helps you make a bet.
赌注经纪人是帮你下注的人。
It's his job to help you make a bet.
他的工作就是帮你下注。
So we often see it in movies.
所以我们经常在电影里看到。
Maybe you are betting on a sports competition, right?
也许你正在赌一场体育比赛，对吧？
And you are betting, I don't know, $10 against this team.
你赌了，我不知道，10美元赌这支队伍输。
So you would go to a bookie to place your bet because there's not really any legal place
所以你会去找赌注经纪人下注，因为并没有真正合法的场所
where you can do it.
可以让你这么做。
Exactly.
没错。
So you want to say, okay, tonight the Chicago Bulls are playing the Suns and you want to
所以你想说，好吧，今晚芝加哥公牛队对阵太阳队，你想
put $100 on the Chicago Bulls.
押100美元在芝加哥公牛队上。
That means they're going to win.
这意味着他们会赢。
So you use a bookie and he helps you put the money down.
所以你找一个赌注经纪人，他帮你把钱押上。
Now usually this is illegal, right?
通常这是非法的，对吧？
Generally it's illegal.
一般来说是非法的。
Yeah.
是的。
It depends.
看情况。
I guess you can go to a bookie at the horse races and it's illegal.
我猜你可以去赛马场找赌注经纪人，那是非法的。
But generally it's illegal, I think.
但一般来说，我认为是非法的。
Okay.
好的。
So a sports bookie, we would say a sports bookie, right?
所以体育赌注经纪人，我们会说体育赌注经纪人，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Interesting words.
有趣的词。
So they're just related to, as we said, addictions and vices, but that's, I guess, kind of what
所以它们都跟，就像我们说的，成瘾和恶习有关，但我想，这大概就是
the whole gambling industry involves, right?
整个赌博行业涉及的内容，对吧？
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
All right.
好的。
So now that we've seen those great words on Language Takeaway, let's move on now to Fluency
那么既然我们在“语言小课堂”里看了这些好词，现在让我们进入“流利度
Builder.
构建”环节。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Okay.
好的。
Fluency Builder is where we get into some of this really exciting stuff, stuff where
“流利度构建”是我们深入一些非常激动人心的内容的地方，这些内容里
we hear some opinions from a person who is not very happy with the gambling industry.
我们听到一个对赌博行业不太满意的人的一些观点。
So this first one, gambling is an industry built on deception.
所以第一个是，赌博是一个建立在欺骗之上的行业。
Okay.
好的。
So it's built on deception.
所以它建立在欺骗之上。
So well, it's an industry, so it's not really tangible.
嗯，它是一个行业，所以不是真正有形的。
Right.
对。
So this is a metaphor.
所以这是一个比喻。
It's like saying that this industry is dependent on something.
就像说这个行业依赖于某样东西。
And what is it dependent on?
它依赖于什么？
Deception.
欺骗。
So what's deception?
那么什么是欺骗？
So to deceive, right?
所以是欺骗，对吧？
That comes from the verb deceive, which basically says like a false appearance, right?
它来自动词 deceive（欺骗），基本上意思是虚假的表象，对吧？
Not really being completely truthful.
不是完全诚实。
Okay.
好的。
This is really good.
这真的很好。
So a lot of movies that we like to watch or theater is based on deception in a good way
所以我们喜欢看的很多电影或戏剧，在好的方面是建立在欺骗之上的，
because you get the idea that something is a certain way, but it really isn't in real
因为你以为事情是某种样子，但在现实生活中其实不是。
life.
所以欺骗在戏剧里可能是好事，但总的来说，欺骗是坏事。
So deception is in the theater, maybe a good thing, but in general, deception is a bad
thing.
所以欺骗在戏剧里可能是好事，但总的来说，欺骗是坏事。
I could say, Marco, I'm sorry I deceived you.
我可以说，Marco，对不起，我欺骗了你。
You lied to me.
你对我撒谎了。
I lied to you.
我对你撒谎了。
Yeah.
是的。
So deception usually involves lies or trying to make something seem like something that
所以欺骗通常涉及谎言，或者试图让某物看起来像
it's not.
它本不是的样子。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So it's this industry is built on deception.
所以这个行业是建立在欺骗之上的。
And he said that the sole purpose of this industry is to make money.
他还说这个行业的唯一目的是赚钱。
Exactly.
没错。
So this, this phrase sole purpose is very, very common.
所以这个短语“sole purpose”（唯一目的）非常非常常见。
You hear this a lot.
你经常听到这个。
Soul, like the soul, like your human soul, like your human soul is spelled differently.
Soul（灵魂），就像人的灵魂，但拼写不同。
S O L E.
S O L E。
So you're talking about the one thing.
所以你在说唯一的东西。
One and only.
唯一的一个。
Yep.
是的。
I only have one love.
我只有一份爱。
I only have one love, my sole pair of shoes.
我只有一份爱，我唯一的一双鞋。
I only have one pair of shoes.
我只有一双鞋。
So it's one thing, but the sole purpose.
所以是唯一的东西，但“sole purpose”。
So the only reason that this industry exists is what?
所以这个行业存在的唯一原因是什么？
For monetary gain.
为了金钱收益。
So monetary, you might have heard of the international monetary fund.
所以 monetary（金钱的），你可能听说过国际货币基金组织。
Exactly.
没错。
The IMF.
国际货币基金组织。
And so monetary refers to money.
所以 monetary 指的是钱。
Money.
钱。
As the door said, it's a gas.
就像门说的，它是气体。
And the gain, which means basically means making it to get more money.
而 gain（收益），基本上意思是获得更多钱。
So that's the point that this person is making that, that the sole purpose of the gambling
所以这就是这个人要表达的观点，赌博行业的唯一目的
industry is to make money.
就是赚钱。
Ouch.
哎哟。
So he's saying there's no other reason to gamble.
所以他在说没有其他理由去赌博。
People are in this industry just to make money.
这个行业里的人只是为了赚钱。
It's greedy.
很贪婪。
Well, I mean, basically you could probably say that almost about almost all the companies,
嗯，我的意思是，基本上你大概可以说几乎所有公司都是这样，
right?
对吧？
What about education companies like ours?
那像我们这样的教育公司呢？
That's different.
那不一样。
Education is very different.
教育非常不同。
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
So what's another industry that has a sole purpose?
那么还有什么行业有唯一目的？
For example, nonprofit organizations, their sole purpose is to help people.
例如，非营利组织，它们的唯一目的是帮助人们。
All right.
好的。
Okay.
I can get into that.
我能接受这个。
Yeah.
是啊。
Cool.
酷。
So sole purpose and monetary gain.
所以是唯一目的和金钱收益。
Very useful phrases.
非常有用的短语。
But let's take another listen to today's dialogue and put to you some of these great,
但让我们再听一遍今天的对话，并向你介绍一些这些很棒、
great new words.
很棒的新词。
Did you hear?
你听到了吗？
The state is thinking of legalizing gambling in our city.
州政府正在考虑在我们城市合法化赌博。
Soon we're going to have amazing hotels and casinos here, which will be good for business.
很快我们这里就会有很棒的酒店和赌场，这对生意有好处。
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗？
Gambling is a vice industry built on deception and fed by the intentional exploitation of
赌博是一种建立在欺骗之上的邪恶行业，通过故意利用
human weakness for the sole purpose of monetary gain.
人性的弱点，以获取金钱收益为唯一目的。
It disgusts me.
这让我感到恶心。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
How does it exploit people?
它怎么剥削人了？
Well, to begin with, gambling is addictive.
嗯，首先，赌博是会上瘾的。
It ruins marriages, destroys families and bankrupts communities.
它破坏婚姻、摧毁家庭、让社区破产。
Once you're addicted, it's very difficult to stop.
一旦上瘾，就很难戒掉。
People have lost their houses, cars and have been left on the street after becoming addicted.
人们在上瘾后失去了房子、车子，流落街头。
Secondly, it exploits because men become addicted to gambling, most often because of the action
其次，它剥削人是因为男性通常因为刺激
and risk.
和风险而上瘾。
Women gamble to escape and senior citizens will start gambling for social interaction.
女性赌博是为了逃避，而老年人开始赌博是为了社交互动。
Underage gamblers often start gambling on sports with friends and then illegal bookies.
未成年赌徒通常从和朋友赌体育比赛开始，然后转向非法赌注。
Geez, now that I think about it, maybe legalizing gambling isn't such a good idea.
天哪，现在想想，也许合法化赌博不是个好主意。
Although I have been to Las Vegas and I didn't become addicted or anything like that.
虽然我去过拉斯维加斯，并没有上瘾或类似情况。
You cannot predict who will become addicted to gambling.
你无法预测谁会赌博上瘾。
Now excuse me, I have a protest rally to organize.
现在请原谅，我要去组织一场抗议集会。
All right, so gambling, what are you, what are your opinions about it?
好了，那么关于赌博，你，你有什么看法？
Pro gambling or anti gambling?
支持赌博还是反对赌博？
OK, well, here's the thing.
好的，嗯，事情是这样的。
Gambling is a sport and it involves money, obviously, but people also don't, I don't
赌博是一项运动，显然涉及金钱，但人们也不应该，我
think should have other people telling them how to spend their money unless they have
认为不应该让别人告诉他们怎么花自己的钱，除非他们
some kind of problem.
有什么问题。
Right?
对吧？
So the law doesn't get involved if you have a drinking problem until you're harmful to
所以如果你有酗酒问题，法律不会介入，直到你
people around you.
对周围的人造成伤害。
So I don't think that it's right for the for the government to be able to say, listen,
所以我认为政府说“听着，
you can't gamble because it's your own money.
你不能赌博”是不对的，因为那是你自己的钱。
If it makes you happy, it makes you happy.
如果它让你开心，那就让你开心。
Interesting.
有意思。
Now we've seen very specific cities or places where you can actually gamble in this way.
我们看到了一些非常特定的城市或地方，你可以这样赌博。
You have Monaco or Las Vegas or Macau more recently.
有摩纳哥、拉斯维加斯，或者更近期的澳门。
Right?
对吧？
So very interesting cities or countries that have been built on the gambling industry,
所以是非常有趣的城市或国家，它们建立在赌博产业之上，
which apparently is a multi-billion dollar industry.
这显然是一个价值数十亿美元的产业。
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
I don't know.
我不知道。
What do you think?
你怎么看？
Are you against gambling?
你反对赌博吗？
Are you for gambling?
你支持赌博吗？
I mean, is it one of those things that you can really...
我的意思是，这是那种你真的可以……
Or do you maybe even like it?
或者你甚至可能喜欢它？
Maybe some people don't even really care for it.
也许有些人根本不在乎它。
They don't find it fun to play blackjack or go to the play a round of poker or something
他们觉得玩二十一点或打一轮扑克之类的
like that.
并不有趣。
Yeah, well, that's their problem.
是啊，嗯，那是他们的问题。
I enjoy it.
我喜欢它。
I think it's fun.
我觉得它很有趣。
I mean, as long as with anything, you do it in moderation.
我的意思是，和任何事情一样，只要适度。
That means you don't do it too much.
这意味着不要做得太多。
I think it's okay.
我觉得没问题。
All right.
好的。
So listeners come to our website, EnglishPod.com to the comment section where you can tell
所以听众们，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，到评论区，在那里你可以告诉我们，
us, well, what are your opinions?
嗯，你的看法是什么？
If you do like gambling, tell us what game you like.
如果你喜欢赌博，告诉我们你喜欢什么游戏。
So, and also if you have any questions or comments, we're always there to answer them,
所以，如果你有任何问题或评论，我们随时都在那里回答，
right?
对吧？
It can be kind of a big issue to talk about because some people are really against it
这可能是一个有点大的话题，因为有些人真的反对它，
and some people are really for it.
有些人真的支持它。
So curious to hear your opinion.
所以很想知道你的意见。
Yeah, we look forward to your opinions and we'll see you guys later.
是啊，我们期待你的意见，我们稍后再见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
See you guys.
再见。